https://www.hostm.com/privacy

Web HostingCompareTourTestimonialsClient LoungeSign Up & PricingPrivacy Policy
At HostM, we believe privacy is a fundamental human right. Your privacy is very important to HostM.Our Privacy Policy is designed to be help protect your personal information in accordance with data protection laws in the European Union (“EU”), the European Economic Area (“EEA”), Switzerland, and the United Kingdom (“UK”), including the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and the UK’s Data Protection Act.Data ControllerThe data controller of this website is HostM Web Hosting, a division of Intuitient Ltd, registered in England and Wales (reg. no. 10826281) at The Garden Suite, 23 Westfield Park, Redland, Bristol, BS6 6LT, United Kingdom (“HostM”, “we”, “us”, or “our”).Collection and Use of Personal InformationHostM’s websites and other online services (“HostM’s Services” or “our Services”) utilize Transport Layer Security / Secure Sockets Layer (“TLS/SSL”) connections, ensuring that information to and from our Services is securely transmitted and encrypted in transit.When you sign up for HostM’s Services, contact us, subscribe to a mailing list, or otherwise utilize our Services, and when we deliver our Services, respond to your request, or otherwise communicate with you, we may collect some information from you.The information that we collect may include your name, email address, organization name and your role, mailing address, phone and fax numbers, Internet Protocol (IP) address, and billing information including credit card details.For security, identity, and age verification for purposes such as resetting your password, we may request information such as date of birth, security questions and answers. We may request identity verification documents where we feel there is a need to further confirm an identity.We collect only the minimum amount of personal information necessary for each task at hand. Each piece of personal information is kept strictly confidential and accessible only to personnel and/or systems that need to deal with that information in the performance of their respective tasks.Such tasks may include identifying you, entering into one or more agreements with you, managing your accounts with us, managing and delivering services that you request from us, securing your accounts and combatting fraud, communicating with you in relation to your requests and/or services you receive from us, and meeting any legal, contractual, business, or other obligations.Billing information such as credit card details are transmitted securely to our payment processing or domain registration partners for processing. As an added level of security, we do not store your credit card details in our own databases.In relation to the processing of your personal information, we only work with payment processors, domain registrars, data center providers, and other service providers whose security protocols meet the requirements of the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), whether they’re located within or outside the EEA.Any personal information that you may have on file with us is never sold to third parties. In the event of an acquisition of, or merger with, HostM or part thereof, we shall ensure that the relevant parties involved meet the requirements of the GDPR prior to any transfer of personal data.Cookies and Other TechnologiesHostM’s Services may use cookies and other technologies to ensure the proper functioning of various features on our websites, such as but not limited to the ability for users to sign in to secure login areas, the protection of online forms against spamming and other malicious activities, and payment processing fraud prevention.As is true of most internet services, some types of information are gathered automatically and stored in log files, such as IP addresses, web browser types, referring pages, operating systems, and date/time stamps, to help us improve your online experience and ensure security.Security MeasuresHostM implements, and takes reasonable steps to ensure that our relevant partners implement, a range of security measures designed to ensure an appropriate of security for the protection of personal and other sensitive information. More information about our security measures can be found on our hosting security page.Data Protection RightsAs a user of HostM’s Services, you have the following data protection rights:You may perform any of the following operations on your personal information you have on file with us:Access, update, or delete your personal informationObject to the processing of your personal informationRequest portability of your personal informationTo do so:If you have Client Lounge access, you may access and update the contact information you have on file with us at any time by visiting the ‘My Profile’ page in the secure Client Lounge, and for other requests you may open a Client Care ticket via the secure Client Lounge.If you do not have Client Lounge access, you may submit your request via our secure contact form. For security reasons, we may request for identity verification to ensure that the request is legitimate before we are allowed to process the request.You may opt out of marketing emails by clicking the Unsubscribe or Manage Your Profile link in the emails concerned.You have the right to withdraw your consent if you had previously consented to the collection and processing of your personal information. This does not affect any previous collection and processing that was performed in accordance with your previous consent.You have the right to complain to a data protection authority in your locality in relation to our collection and processing of your personal information.The above notwithstanding:Where there is an ongoing business need to retain personal information that we have collected from you, including but not limited to the provision of a service that relies on the availability or processing of said information, or to comply with legal, tax, or accounting requirements, said information shall be retained.Where there is no longer an ongoing business need to retain personal information, said information shall be deleted or anonymized.Data Processing AgreementIf you are a client, we may be processing personal information on your behalf as part of the nature of our Services, such as when you host websites and email on our servers. To that end, a Data Processing Agreement pursuant to the GDPR is included as an addendum to our Terms of Service.Minimum Age RequirementsPersons below a certain age depending upon their location (“the relevant minimum age”) are prohibited from using our Services or otherwise providing us with personal information, as follows:age 13, for persons outside the EU including Norway and the United States, and for persons in the Czech Republic, Denmark, Finland, Ireland, Latvia, Poland, Spain, Sweden, and the UK;age 14, for persons in Austria;age 15, for persons in Greece; andage 16, for persons in France, Germany, Hungary, Lithuania, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, Slovakia, and any other EU member state not listed above.HostM does not knowingly collect personal information from persons below the relevant minimum age.If you learn that a person under the relevant minimum age has provided us with personal information in violation of this Privacy Policy, please let us know via our secure contact form.Changes to this Privacy PolicyHostM may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, including to comply with changes to the law. Please frequently check this page to review any changes to this Privacy Policy.Privacy Questions Should you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please feel free to reach out to us via the secure contact form if you’re a visitor, or via the Client Care ticket system located in the secure Client Lounge if you’re a client.ProductsWeb HostingHTTPS HostingEmail HostingSoftwareFREE SSL CertificatesHostingWordPress HostingLiveCode HostingcPanel HostingMariaDB HostingRapidWeaver HostingExploreSign Up & PricingClient TestimonialsAbout UsQuick TourPlugin Web AppsSupportClient LoungeFrequent QuestionsTutorials & GuidesContact UsCopyright © 2020 HostM Web Hosting. All rights reserved.Terms of Service·Acceptable Use Policy·Privacy Policy·Site Map
